DAN ROM

danrom2210@gmail.com +27 (079) 034 4465

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am currently in my final year at the University of Cape Town studying towards a degree in Electrical and Computer Engineering. My passion for the content I am learning allows me to excel in my studies. I have a friendly and outgoing personality and am able to cope well in high-stress situations. To view projects I have worked on throughout my studies, both part of and external to the university curriculum, please view my portfolio

EDUCATION

University of Cape Town

March 2021 - Present

Studying towards a Bachelor of Science in Engineering in Electrical and Computer Engineering Faculty of Engineering and the Built Environment

King David Victory Park High School

2016-2020

IEB National Senior Certificate

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Tutor

January 2021 - November 2023

Made use of Zoom online platform to provide support for students in Grade 7 - Grade 12 in: Accounting, Afrikaans, Hebrew, Information Technology, Mathematics and Physical Science

Think Camp Coding Tutor

September 2022 - February 2024

Facilitated multiple classes of 3-6 students at a time, taking them through the Think Camp coding syllabus. Students' ages range between 9 and 16 and languages taught include Scratch, LiveCode and Python.

Synthesis Student Intern

December 2023

Took part in the Synthesis Vacation Work program. My project involved building a full scale application for internal office use - making use of React JS for the front end and Python for the back end.

Innovation Labs Tutor

July 2024 - Present

As a tutor for Innovation Labs, I was involved in the running of a weekly extra-curricular activity at Reddam House Constantia High School where students are able to learn the fundamentals of Electrical Engineering. This includes basic circuit theory, an introduction to microcontrollers as well as practical projects where the students could use their knowledge to build a working project - often involving integrating a sensor with a microcontroller.

Signals and Systems Tutor

July 2024 - October 2024

In the final year of my undergraduate degree, I was employed as a tutor for the second year Signals and Systems (EEE2047S). Responsibilities included running tutorial sessions for the students, assisting in any questions they had regarding the course content. I also assisted in the marking of tests, labs and assignments.

ACADEMIC AWARDS

University Awards

· Included in Dean's Merit List, 2021, 2022 and 2023.

High School Awards

- · Graduated Summa Cum Laude (average over 90 percent) with 9 distinctions from King David Victory Park High School, 2020.
- · Ranked in the top 1 percent of IEB students in the English Home Language final examination, 2020.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

- · Treasurer of the South African Union of Jewish Students (SAUJS) Western Cape, 2022-2023
- · Head Boy of King David Victory Park High School, 2019-2020.
- · Chosen to represent King David Victory Park on the **Johannesburg Junior Council**, 2018-2019.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Johannesburg Holocaust and Genocide Centre

April 2020

'Together We Remember Vigil'

- · The 'Together We Remember' Non-profit Organisation holds a 24 hour virtual Genocide Awareness event every year. Genocide museums from 24 different countries each put together a one hour presentation.
- · My responsibilities included finding students from various schools to participate in South Africa's contribution, assisting in deciding what content should be in the presentation as well as putting together the presentation on Microsoft PowerPoint

Johannesburg Junior Council

October 2018 - October 2019

Outreach Committee

- · I was selected as one of two students to represent my school on the Johannesburg Junior Council
- · This organization aims to give the youth a platform to give back to South African society by reaching out and assisting those in need
- · As part of the outreach committee, I spent many hours collecting essential goods for orphanages, old-age homes and women shelters.
- · The 'Dean Walt's Kids Carnival' was our biggest event. Over 350 disadvantaged children from multiple orphanages attended this event on the field of Edenglen High-School where they were provided with a warm meal, 'goodie' bags to take home and entertainment for the day.

SKILLS

Programming Skills:

Experience in Python, Java, Embedded C, C++, MATLAB and React JS.

Public Speaking:

Member of the winning team out of 108 schools in the 'Speech and Drama College High School Public Speaking Festival' in the Impromptu section (2019)

Languages:

Fluent in English, intermediate proficiency in Afrikaans and Hebrew